Guide to the International Brotherhood of Teamsters Locals and Joint Councils General records, 1911-2010 IBT0076
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
IBT Locals and Joint Councils - General
1911-2010
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
IBT0076
2 Linear Feet
This collection consists of documentation on a variety of IBT local unions and joint councils.
Scope and Contents
This collection houses miscellaneous printed matter, receipts, booklets, and event handouts from a variety of IBT Local Unions and Joint Councils. Materials are dated from 1911 to 2010.
Arrangement
The collection is arranged individually by IBT local.
Conditions Governing Access
This collection is open for research.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Materials were transferred from the International Brotherhood of Teamsters.
Biographical / Historical
LOCAL UNIONS There are hundreds of Teamsters local unions across North America. The local unions and their members are the heart and backbone of the union. Unlike other labor unions, the Teamsters Union is structured to promote strong local unions, and strong local leaders. Since the locals negotiate most Teamsters contracts and provide most of the services to the members, they keep most of the dues money. Locals retain their own expert labor lawyers, certified public accountants, full-time business agents, organizers, and clerical staff. The members of each local elect their own officers, devise their own structure, and vote on their own bylaws, compatible with the International Constitution and Bylaws. While enjoying their independence, the locals benefit from the expertise and assistance of the International Union, and of the various conferences and councils in the union's structure. JOINT COUNCILS Teamsters Joint Councils are set up in areas with three or more local unions. Joint Councils help coordinate Teamsters activities in those areas. They also help solve problems and decide some jurisdictional and judicial matters.
Bib#
17257795
Labor unions -- United States -- History -- 20th century; Labor unions
- Local 743 Sticker, undated (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Local 45 1-#2 Great Falls, Montana, 1910-2010 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Local 405 Records Storage, 1911-1956 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Local 531-#2, Bozeman, Montana, 1914-2010 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Local 345: 25th Anniversary Program, October 20, 1928 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Local 368: "The Voice of the Soft Drink Worker", 1936 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Local 52: Fifth Anniversary Banquet, 1936 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Local 603-St. Louis, Mo. Industrial Bank Deposit Receipts, 1936 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Local 52: 15th Anniversary Banquet Program, November6, 1948 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Local 366: Spring Dance Program, Receipts, and "A Plan of Group Insurance Benefits", 1952-1962 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Local 1205-Memo to James R. Hoffa, August 25, 1958 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Local 743: "Resolution on Retirement", January 7, 1963 (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Local 52:30th Anniversary Banquet and Testimonial Dinner, April 4, 1964 (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Joint Council No. 13-"Teamsters Annual Charity Show", October 23, 1964 (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Local 299-32nd Anniversary Booklet, 1965 (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Local No. 16 & 73-"Testimonial Dinner Honoring JAmes R. Hoffa", October 22, 1965 (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Local 816: "The 816 Express" Vol 7 & 8, 1965-1974 (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Teamster Joint Council Credit Union: "The Counciler" Volume 8, No. 2, May-June, 1970 (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Local 285-President Isaac Litwak Retirement Dinner Programs and Plaque from the National Association for the Advancement of Colored People, 1966-1972 (Box 2, Folder 9)
- "Local Union445 Annual Dinner-Dance at the Concord Hotel-Kiamesha Lake, NY, N.Y." Program, October 12, 1968 (Box 2, Folder 10)
- Local 676: "Stewards 5th Annual Dinner" Program, May 26, 1972 (Box 2, Folder 11)
- Eastern Conference of Teamsters-Bethesda, MD -"Mileage Chart", 1972 (Box 2, Folder 12)
- "Teamsters Local Union 391: The First Forty Then and Now", September 9, 1978 (Box 2, Folder 13)
- Local 211: "50th Anniversary Program", November 5, 1978 (Box 2, Folder 14)
- Local 959:-Noteworth Years", 1980s (Box 2, Folder 15)
- Local 115: Philadelphia Inquierer Magazine, September 4, 1983 (Box 2, Folder 16)
- Local 1038 Handout-"Bob Knox Has Done to Loca 1038 what Ron Carey Has Done to the IBT"", 1993 (Box 2, Folder 17)
- Local 391 Press Release-"RV Durham Blasts Teamster Presidents Record", June 10, 1994 (Box 2, Folder 18)
- Joint Council No. 64-Memo from President Jack Powers, July 30, 1994 (Box 2, Folder 19)
- Joint Council No.32 Memo to Ron Carey, July 7, 1994 (Box 2, Folder 20)
- Local 710-Memo from Secretary Treasurer Frank Wsol to President Ron Carey, July 8, 1994 (Box 2, Folder 21)
- Local 346-Memo from Secretary-Treasurer Clarence LaBorde, July, 1994 (Box 2, Folder 22)
- Local 705-Memo from Jo Pressler to Leroy Ellis, August 1, 1994 (Box 2, Folder 23)
- Local 214 P.A.C. Report, Vol. 2, No.1, Winter, 1994 (Box 2, Folder 24)
- Joint Council No.7-"Teamsters Assistance Program of Northern California" Handouts, 1995-2005 (Box 2, Folder 25)
- Local 2000-"Contract Campaign Bulletin 1", 1998 (Box 2, Folder 26)
- Local 364: "The History of Teamsters Local 364", 1999 (Box 2, Folder 27)
- Local 560-Court Transcript, February-April, 1999 (Box 2, Folder 28)
- Local 710: "Stewards Seminar", April 16-17, 1999 (Box 3, Folder 1)
- Local 190: Reports on the 2005 & 2007 Legislatures (Box 3, Folder 2)
- Local 25: 2007 & 2008 Calendars (Box 3, Folder 3)
- Local 901: "Union de Tronquistas Invecible-50 Anos de dignidad y compromiso" by Marcos R. Pastrana Fuentes, 2007 (Box 3, Folder 4)
- Local 82: Programs and newsletters, 2007-2008 (Box 3, Folder 5)
- Local 170-75th Anniversary Program, November 15, 2008 (Box 3, Folder 6)
- Local 135: Flyers, February, 2009 (Box 3, Folder 7)
- Local 366: Daniel J. Murphy Dinner-Receipts, July, 1948 (Box 4, Folder 1)
- Local 766: News clippings, 1954-1959 (Box 4, Folder 2)
- Local 247: The Detroit News clipping-"Backer of Hoffa Ouster Move is Beaten", November 11, 1958 (Box 4, Folder 3)
- Local 107: Christmas Program, Photos, and Voting Flyers, 1983-2005 (Box 4, Folder 4)
- Joint Council No. 43 Convention Booklet, 1959 (Box 4, Folder 5)
- Local Union No. 743 Booklet, Undated (Box 4, Folder 6)
- The American Friends of Yitzhak Rabin 20 Year Anniversary Booklet, 2015 (Box 4, Folder 7)
- Photographs of Jessie Jackson on Government Takeover of Unions- Memphis, TN, 1988 (Box 4, Folder 8)
- Local 814 Blank Forms, Undated (Box 4, Folder 9)
- Charles Deaner Local 771 Obituary, 1999 (Box 4, Folder 10)
- Teamsters Local 190 Celebration, 2011 (Box 4, Folder 11)
- Gus Janossy Local 848 Retirement Photograph Book, 1977 (Box 4, Folder 12)
- Log Book by Dick Collins, 1983 (Box 4, Folder 13)
- Local 560 Letter of Compliments, 1988 (Box 4, Folder 14)
- Teamsters Pension Trust Fund Philadelphia and Vicinity, 1973 (Box 4, Folder 15)
- Petitions, Local 814, 1986 (Box 4, Folder 16)
- Cleveland Teamsters Credit Union Correspondence and Info, 1954 (Box 4, Folder 17)
- Local 170, Local 952 Buttons, 1973; IBT 0076 (Box 5, Folder 1)
- Local 71, Local 364 Buttons, 1998 (Box 5, Folder 2)
- Local 682, 690, 830 Buttons, 2011-2016 (Box 5, Folder 3)
- Local 639 pin, Local 408 cufflink, ND (Box 5, Folder 20)
- Local 710 Buttons, 1983 (Box 5, Folder 4)
- Local 732 Button, 1908 (Box 5, Folder 5)
- Local 272 pins, ND (Box 5, Folder 6)
- Local 70, 85, 120, 156, 731, 801,799 Buttons, 1936-1943 (Box 5, Folder 7)
- Local 728 Button and Stickers (Box 5, Folder 8)
- Local 371, 607, 407 pins, 1950-2003 (Box 5, Folder 9)
- Local 25 button and stickers (Box 5, Folder 10)
- Local 31 pins, ND (Box 5, Folder 11)
- Local 429 buttons, 1976-1978 (Box 5, Folder 12)
- Local 251 buttons and stickers, 2011 (Box 5, Folder 13)
- Motion Picture Division Pins, ND (Box 5, Folder 14)
- Local 399 stickers, ND (Box 5, Folder 15)
- Local 320 pin and stickers (Box 5, Folder 16)
- Local 856 plaque, ND (Box 5, Folder 17)
- Local 574 buttons, ND (Box 5, Folder 18)
- Local 636 buttons, 1941 (Box 5, Folder 19)
- Buttons from Various Locals, IBT 0076 (Box 5, Folder 15)
- General Teamster Membership Cards [3 different cards], IBT0076 (Box SHARED Box 31, Folder 13)
- Payroll Check [Local 407?], August, 6, 1970; IBT0076 (Box SHARED Box 31, Folder 14)
- Local 259, Newspaper Chauffeurs Distributors and helpers, 25th Anniversary Souvenir, 1930; IBT0076 (Box SHARED Box 31, Folder 15)